<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rstats on Yet Another Iteration</title>
    <link>/tags/rstats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rstats on Yet Another Iteration</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Springer Books about Data Science, Statistics and R</title>
      <link>/2020/04/free-springer-books-about-data-science-statistics-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/free-springer-books-about-data-science-statistics-and-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the Coronavirus outbreak having an unprecedented impact on education, Springer Nature is launching a global program to support learning and teaching at higher education institutions worldwide, enabling to access for free more than 500 key textbooks across Springer Nature’s eBook subject collections. These books will be available via SpringerLink until at least the end of July. See some Data Science and Statistics (with R) related books we selected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ggmap and gganimation to visualize oil spill in Brazil coastline</title>
      <link>/2019/12/using-ggmap-and-gganimation-to-visualize-oil-spill-in-brazil-coastilne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/using-ggmap-and-gganimation-to-visualize-oil-spill-in-brazil-coastilne/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In 2019, a crude oil spill struck more than 2,000 kilometers off the coast of Brazil’s Northeast and Southeast, affecting more than 400 beaches in more than 200 different municipalities. The first reports of the spill occurred at the end of August with sightings still spreading later this year. This post explores the sighting records available on the IBAMA website to view the impact of the leak using ggmap and gganimation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: Pizzas and Monsters</title>
      <link>/2019/10/tidytuesday-pizzas-and-monsters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/tidytuesday-pizzas-and-monsters/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We learn from the masters, doing the &lt;em&gt;math&lt;/em&gt; by ourselves, so, in this post we reproduce two data analysis from David Robinson’s &lt;em&gt;#TidyTuesday&lt;/em&gt; screencasts, the first one about the horro movie ratings dataset where he uses a lasso regression to predict the ratings of a movie based on genre, cast and plot. The second is about a dataset of pizza ratings in NYC and other cities. There are goods data handling tricks using tidyverse in these analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Análise de Sentimentos via Emojis em chat do WhatsApp</title>
      <link>/2019/10/an%C3%A1lise-de-sentimentos-via-emojis-em-chat-do-whatsapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/an%C3%A1lise-de-sentimentos-via-emojis-em-chat-do-whatsapp/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;O pacote rwhatsapp, desenvolvido e disponibilizado por Johannes Grubber, permite manipular diretamente os arquivos TXT (e ZIP) de uma conversão exportada pelo aplicativo WhatsApp, importando os dados para um data.frame e disponibilizando-os para análise de maneira simples e direta. Ao esbarrar com esse pacote no Twitter decidi explorar uma conversão de um dos meus grupos e fazer uma análise de sentimentos através dos Emoji’s enviados pelos membros do grupo, confira como ficou…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Fitbit and Polar H7 heart rate data</title>
      <link>/2019/03/comparing-fitbit-and-polar-h7-heart-rate-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/comparing-fitbit-and-polar-h7-heart-rate-data/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;How good is the Fitbit measures comparing to Polar H7? The wearable Fitbit bracelet measures the heart rate based on the expansion and contraction of the capillaries in the skin throught measurement of the reflection and absorption of LED lights, different from the method used heart rate monitor Polar H7, which captures the electrical signals from the heart beat. In this post, we’ll access a WebAPI using OAuth2.0 to get Fitbit data and compare it with those obtained by a Polar H7, imported from a GPX file during the same training session.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operações Long-Short através de Cointegração usando R</title>
      <link>/2018/08/operando-long-short-usando-cointegracao-em-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/operando-long-short-usando-cointegracao-em-r/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Operações Long-Short por Cointegração é uma estratégia de investimento em ativos que consiste em encontrar pares de ações (índices ou &lt;em&gt;commodities&lt;/em&gt;) que mantém um padrão de comportamento estável e previsível (equilíbrio estacionário) com variações de curto prazo que permita ser explorado em operações de Long (compra) e Short (venda) do par. Este R-Notebook refaz o passo-a-passo nas análises estatísticas necessárias para detectar e operação essa estratégia de mercado.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science das Cervejas (2/2)</title>
      <link>/2018/02/data-science-das-cervejas-2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/data-science-das-cervejas-2-2/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Esta é a &lt;a href=&#34;(https://yetanotheriteration.netlify.com/2018/02/data-science-das-cervejas-1-2/)&#34;&gt;segunda parte&lt;/a&gt; do post sobre &lt;em&gt;text mining&lt;/em&gt; usando como base, a avaliações de cervejas extraído de um blog na web. Neste post analisaremos as semelhanças entre os diversos tipos através de suas características de sabor, cor e malte. Quais tipos de cervejas são semelhantes entre si e como tipos semelhantes ainda se diferem. Esse tipo de análise é um aspecto importante no campo de &lt;em&gt;Data Science&lt;/em&gt;, pois permite construir um processo de “sugestões” para consumo, tomando como base o gosto atual dos usuários.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science das Cervejas (1/2)</title>
      <link>/2018/02/data-science-das-cervejas-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/data-science-das-cervejas-1-2/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Neste post vamos extrair, via &lt;em&gt;data scraping&lt;/em&gt;, textos e dados de um blog de avaliações de cerveja para encontrar os termos que melhor caracterizam e descrevem os diversos tipos de cerveja através das descrições dos sabores, cores e maltes das mesmas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>