<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forecast on Yet Another Iteration</title>
    <link>https://yetanotheriteration.netlify.com/tags/forecast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forecast on Yet Another Iteration</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yetanotheriteration.netlify.com/tags/forecast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Fantasy Games Using Monte Carlo Simulations</title>
      <link>https://yetanotheriteration.netlify.com/2018/10/forecasting-fantasy-games-using-monte-carlo-simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yetanotheriteration.netlify.com/2018/10/forecasting-fantasy-games-using-monte-carlo-simulations/</guid>
      <description>The football season is back, and with it the Fantasy Game! In this post, we will simulate the results and the scoring of my Fantasy League games. To do that, we’ll project the scoring of teams using Monte Carlo simulation with data scraped from sites that predicts players’ performances. We will combine the various possible scores of a team’s players to estimate the team’s score distribution, and then compare with the opposing team, and finally compute each team’s chances of winning and losing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Facebook&#39;s Prophet to forecast my weight loss</title>
      <link>https://yetanotheriteration.netlify.com/2018/07/forecasting-my-weight-using-facebook-s-prophet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yetanotheriteration.netlify.com/2018/07/forecasting-my-weight-using-facebook-s-prophet/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we’ll try to forecast my weight using Forecast and Facebook’s Prophet packages. We’ll see what is the performance from Facebook’s method in a simple case of forecast.
Recently, in the beginning of march, I went to a Nutritionist who recommended me to start a regime to lost some weight. As a good practice in these situations, short feedback cycles are essential to (re)build good habits, so I start to weigh myself almost daily, and record the values in a spreadsheet to follow my progress.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>