<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yet Another Iteration</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yet Another Iteration</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Tidymodels Exercises</title>
      <link>/2021/06/my-tidymodels-exercises/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/06/my-tidymodels-exercises/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;“The only way to learn mathematics is to do mathematics.” - Paul Halmos. Taking time out of the day-to-day rush to finally learn how to use &lt;code&gt;{tidymodels}&lt;/code&gt; for machine learning. These are the notebooks that I did to enter in this universe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chilling Effect Resulting from Mass Surveillance</title>
      <link>/2021/03/chilling-effect-resulting-from-mass-surveillance.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/chilling-effect-resulting-from-mass-surveillance.en-us/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/lightable/lightable.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2769645&#34;&gt;Jon Penney (2016)&lt;/a&gt; explored whether the widespread publicity about NSA/PRISM surveillance (i.e., &lt;em&gt;the Snowden revelations&lt;/em&gt;) in June 2013 was associated with a sharp and sudden decrease in traffic to Wikipedia articles on topics that raise privacy concerns. This post tries to reproduce some of this findings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are we forgetting our past faster?</title>
      <link>/2021/02/bit-by-bit-ngram-google-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/02/bit-by-bit-ngram-google-books/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In a widely discussed paper, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dash.harvard.edu/bitstream/handle/1/8899722/MichelScience2011.pdf&#34;&gt;Michel and colleagues (2011)&lt;/a&gt; analyzed the content of more than five million digitized books in an attempt to identify long-term cultural trends. The data that they used has now been released as the Google NGrams dataset, and so we can use the data to replicate and extend some of their work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 | Days 8 to 10</title>
      <link>/2020/12/adventcode_part_03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/12/adventcode_part_03/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Advent of Code is an Advent calendar of small programming puzzles for a variety of skill sets and skill levels that can be solved in any programming language you like. These are my six solutions to the ‘Advent of Code 2020’ puzzles, from day 8 to day 10, using R.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 | Day 07 | Playing with Graphs</title>
      <link>/2020/12/advent-of-code-2020-day-07-playing-with-graphs.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/12/advent-of-code-2020-day-07-playing-with-graphs.en-us/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/lightable/lightable.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In this post, we explore the day 7 puzzles of the Advent Of Code 2020 using network analysis through &lt;code&gt;tidygraph&lt;/code&gt; package, allowing us generate a simple, direct and small code to solve them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 | Days 4 to 6</title>
      <link>/2020/12/advent-of-code-2020-part_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/12/advent-of-code-2020-part_02/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/lightable/lightable.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Advent of Code is an Advent calendar of small programming puzzles for a variety of skill sets and skill levels that can be solved in any programming language you like. These are my six solutions to the ‘Advent of Code 2020’ puzzles, from day 4 to day 6, using R.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code 2020 | Day 1 to 3</title>
      <link>/2020/12/advent-of-code-2020-part_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/12/advent-of-code-2020-part_01/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/lightable/lightable.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Advent of Code is an Advent calendar of small programming puzzles for a variety of skill sets and skill levels that can be solved in any programming language you like. These are my six solutions to the ‘Advent of Code 2020’ puzzles, from day 1 to day 3, using R.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerando Indicadores Ágeis com R, Jenkins e Docker</title>
      <link>/2020/05/gerando-indicadores-%C3%A1geis-com-r-jenkins-e-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/gerando-indicadores-%C3%A1geis-com-r-jenkins-e-docker/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Sempre se comenta a grande versatilidade do &lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt;, com capacidade de participar de todas as etapas de um fluxo de análise de dados. Neste post descrevo um trabalho de implantação de técnicas ágeis de desenvolvimento de software em um grande banco brasileiro que também acabou implementando um &lt;em&gt;pipeline de aquisição, análise e divulgação de dados&lt;/em&gt; sobre métricas e indicadores de produtividade, qualidade e previsibilidade que foi todo implementando usando &lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt; e automatizado através de &lt;em&gt;Jenkins&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Docker&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;GitLab&lt;/em&gt; e &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/dashboard_cover.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Springer Books about Data Science, Statistics and R</title>
      <link>/2020/04/free-springer-books-about-data-science-statistics-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/free-springer-books-about-data-science-statistics-and-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the Coronavirus outbreak having an unprecedented impact on education, Springer Nature is launching a global program to support learning and teaching at higher education institutions worldwide, enabling to access for free more than 500 key textbooks across Springer Nature’s eBook subject collections. These books will be available via SpringerLink until at least the end of July. See some Data Science and Statistics (with R) related books we selected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ggmap and gganimation to visualize oil spill in Brazil coastline</title>
      <link>/2019/12/using-ggmap-and-gganimation-to-visualize-oil-spill-in-brazil-coastilne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/using-ggmap-and-gganimation-to-visualize-oil-spill-in-brazil-coastilne/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In 2019, a crude oil spill struck more than 2,000 kilometers off the coast of Brazil’s Northeast and Southeast, affecting more than 400 beaches in more than 200 different municipalities. The first reports of the spill occurred at the end of August with sightings still spreading later this year. This post explores the sighting records available on the IBAMA website to view the impact of the leak using ggmap and gganimation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: Pizzas and Monsters</title>
      <link>/2019/10/tidytuesday-pizzas-and-monsters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/tidytuesday-pizzas-and-monsters/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We learn from the masters, doing the &lt;em&gt;math&lt;/em&gt; by ourselves, so, in this post we reproduce two data analysis from David Robinson’s &lt;em&gt;#TidyTuesday&lt;/em&gt; screencasts, the first one about the horro movie ratings dataset where he uses a lasso regression to predict the ratings of a movie based on genre, cast and plot. The second is about a dataset of pizza ratings in NYC and other cities. There are goods data handling tricks using tidyverse in these analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Análise de Sentimentos via Emojis em chat do WhatsApp</title>
      <link>/2019/10/an%C3%A1lise-de-sentimentos-via-emojis-em-chat-do-whatsapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/an%C3%A1lise-de-sentimentos-via-emojis-em-chat-do-whatsapp/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;O pacote rwhatsapp, desenvolvido e disponibilizado por Johannes Grubber, permite manipular diretamente os arquivos TXT (e ZIP) de uma conversão exportada pelo aplicativo WhatsApp, importando os dados para um data.frame e disponibilizando-os para análise de maneira simples e direta. Ao esbarrar com esse pacote no Twitter decidi explorar uma conversão de um dos meus grupos e fazer uma análise de sentimentos através dos Emoji’s enviados pelos membros do grupo, confira como ficou…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Brazil BH - O Mito da Agilidade: Bom, Rápido e Barato</title>
      <link>/2019/09/agile-brazil-bh-o-mito-da-agilidade-bom-rapido-e-barato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/agile-brazil-bh-o-mito-da-agilidade-bom-rapido-e-barato/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Em setembro de 2019, em visita à Belo Horizonte, tive a oportunidade de palestrar em um Meetup organizado pelos colegas de empresa e também no maior evento de agilidade do país, o Agile Brazil. Em ambos, o tema da palestra foi &amp;ldquo;O mito da agilidade: bom, rápido e barato! Será mesmo que Scrum e Ágil entregam &amp;lsquo;o dobro pela metade do tempo&amp;rsquo;?&amp;rdquo;. Nesta palestra discuto quais são as práticas ágeis que mais promovem produtividade e qualidade no desenvolvimento ágil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends: Ready-Ready, PO Team &amp; Heijunka</title>
      <link>/2019/04/agile-trends-ready-ready-po-team-heijunka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/agile-trends-ready-ready-po-team-heijunka/</guid>
      <description>Durante a transformação ágil da CI&amp;amp;T, aprendemos como a existência de um Product Owner completo, capaz de desempenhar tudo que o papel exige, é crítica não só para a qualidade do produto como também para a performance do próprio time de desenvolvimento. Hoje, frequentemente, encontramos os mesmos problemas decorrentes da atuação incompleta do PO em clientes que estão começando a sua jornada ágil. Neste post compartilho a minha apresentação realizada no Agile Trends 2019 que fala a respeito da importancia deste papel na agilidade e como resolver alguns gaps de atuação.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Fitbit and Polar H7 heart rate data</title>
      <link>/2019/03/comparing-fitbit-and-polar-h7-heart-rate-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/comparing-fitbit-and-polar-h7-heart-rate-data/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;How good is the Fitbit measures comparing to Polar H7? The wearable Fitbit bracelet measures the heart rate based on the expansion and contraction of the capillaries in the skin throught measurement of the reflection and absorption of LED lights, different from the method used heart rate monitor Polar H7, which captures the electrical signals from the heart beat. In this post, we’ll access a WebAPI using OAuth2.0 to get Fitbit data and compare it with those obtained by a Polar H7, imported from a GPX file during the same training session.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The learning process in organizational change</title>
      <link>/2019/02/design-for-people-learning-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/design-for-people-learning-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much of the my work about lean/digital consulting and change management is to make people learning. Learning new concepts, new values, new ways of doing a job or an activity, learning to managing and lead using new tools and methods, and also involves unlearning concepts and points of view built over time, to make room for the new knowledge. So, learning is a key aspect, and also a barrier, for the people involved in the change or transformation processes. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explore and summarize the key concepts in the great &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/usablelearning&#34;&gt;Julie Dirksen&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B018OJP5QW/ref=dbs_a_def_rwt_hsch_vapi_taft_p1_i0&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Design for How People Learning&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; book. I frequently review these points when preparing a change roadmap for a team, department or company, the success of a change is direct linked with how people will effectively learn and be capable to use new knowledge in their daily work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow and Keras with R</title>
      <link>/2019/01/tensorflow-and-keras-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/tensorflow-and-keras-with-r/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I’ll start series of posts about &lt;a href=&#34;https://keras.io/&#34;&gt;Keras&lt;/a&gt;, a high-level &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_neural_network&#34;&gt;neural networks&lt;/a&gt; API developed with a focus on enabling fast experimentation, running on top of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tensorflow.org&#34;&gt;TensorFlow&lt;/a&gt;, but using its &lt;a href=&#34;https://keras.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;R interface&lt;/a&gt;. To start, we’ll review our &lt;a href=&#34;https://yetanotheriteration.netlify.com/2018/01/implementing-lenet-with-mxnet-in-r/&#34;&gt;LeNet implemantation with MXNET&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://yann.lecun.com/exdb/mnist/&#34;&gt;MNIST problem&lt;/a&gt;, a traditional “&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%22Hello,_World!%22_program&#34;&gt;Hello World&lt;/a&gt;” in the Neural Network world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Agile User Stories Slicing</title>
      <link>/2019/01/slicing-and-dicing-agile-user-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/slicing-and-dicing-agile-user-stories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A chave para a implantação de uma cultura de entrega ágil e passo importantíssimo para viabilizar DevOps, a quebra adequada de histórias de usuário é também um dos maiores desafios para as equipes que são novas na abordagem ágil. Frequentemente a mudança do que chamamos de &amp;ldquo;divisão horizontal&amp;rdquo; para “fatia vertical” exige uma mudança de racional de desenvolvimento que as equipes muitas vezes não estão acostumadas. &amp;ldquo;Bem, nosso sistema é muito complexo&amp;rdquo;, ou &amp;ldquo;precisamos construir recursos realmente grandes ou nossos usuários não conseguirão usar&amp;rdquo; são desculpas comuns nesta situação.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Fantasy Games Using Monte Carlo Simulations</title>
      <link>/2018/10/forecasting-fantasy-games-using-monte-carlo-simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/forecasting-fantasy-games-using-monte-carlo-simulations/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The football season is back, and with it the Fantasy Game! In this post, we will simulate the results and the scoring of my Fantasy League games. To do that, we’ll project the scoring of teams using &lt;code&gt;Monte Carlo&lt;/code&gt; simulation with data scraped from sites that predicts players’ performances. We will combine the various possible scores of a team’s players to estimate the team’s score distribution, and then compare with the opposing team, and finally compute each team’s chances of winning and losing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operações Long-Short através de Cointegração usando R</title>
      <link>/2018/08/operando-long-short-usando-cointegracao-em-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/operando-long-short-usando-cointegracao-em-r/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Operações Long-Short por Cointegração é uma estratégia de investimento em ativos que consiste em encontrar pares de ações (índices ou &lt;em&gt;commodities&lt;/em&gt;) que mantém um padrão de comportamento estável e previsível (equilíbrio estacionário) com variações de curto prazo que permita ser explorado em operações de Long (compra) e Short (venda) do par. Este R-Notebook refaz o passo-a-passo nas análises estatísticas necessárias para detectar e operação essa estratégia de mercado.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Facebook&#39;s Prophet to forecast my weight loss</title>
      <link>/2018/07/forecasting-my-weight-using-facebook-s-prophet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/forecasting-my-weight-using-facebook-s-prophet/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll try to forecast my weight using Forecast and Facebook’s Prophet packages. We’ll see what is the performance from Facebook’s method in a simple case of forecast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science das Cervejas (2/2)</title>
      <link>/2018/02/data-science-das-cervejas-2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/data-science-das-cervejas-2-2/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Esta é a &lt;a href=&#34;(https://yetanotheriteration.netlify.com/2018/02/data-science-das-cervejas-1-2/)&#34;&gt;segunda parte&lt;/a&gt; do post sobre &lt;em&gt;text mining&lt;/em&gt; usando como base, a avaliações de cervejas extraído de um blog na web. Neste post analisaremos as semelhanças entre os diversos tipos através de suas características de sabor, cor e malte. Quais tipos de cervejas são semelhantes entre si e como tipos semelhantes ainda se diferem. Esse tipo de análise é um aspecto importante no campo de &lt;em&gt;Data Science&lt;/em&gt;, pois permite construir um processo de “sugestões” para consumo, tomando como base o gosto atual dos usuários.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science das Cervejas (1/2)</title>
      <link>/2018/02/data-science-das-cervejas-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/data-science-das-cervejas-1-2/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Neste post vamos extrair, via &lt;em&gt;data scraping&lt;/em&gt;, textos e dados de um blog de avaliações de cerveja para encontrar os termos que melhor caracterizam e descrevem os diversos tipos de cerveja através das descrições dos sabores, cores e maltes das mesmas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kNN Analysis on MNIST with 97% accuracy</title>
      <link>/2018/01/knn-analysis-on-mnist-with-97-accuracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/knn-analysis-on-mnist-with-97-accuracy/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/htmlwidgets/htmlwidgets.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/plotly-binding/plotly.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/typedarray/typedarray.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/jquery/jquery.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/crosstalk/css/crosstalk.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/crosstalk/js/crosstalk.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/plotly-htmlwidgets-css/plotly-htmlwidgets.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/plotly-main/plotly-latest.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Usually Yann LeCun’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://yann.lecun.com/exdb/mnist/index.html&#34;&gt;MNIST database&lt;/a&gt; is used to explore &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_neural_network&#34;&gt;Artificial Neural Network&lt;/a&gt; architectures for image recognition problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;/2018/01/implementing-lenet-with-mxnet-in-r/&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; the use of a ANN (LeNet architecture) implemented using mxnet to resolve this classification problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in this post, we’ll see that the MNIST problem isn’t a difficult one, only resolved by ANNs, analyzing the data set we can see that is possible, with a high degree of precision, resolving this classification problem with a simple &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K-nearest_neighbors_algorithm&#34;&gt;k-nearest neighbors algorithm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing LeNet with MXNET in R</title>
      <link>/2018/01/implementing-lenet-with-mxnet-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/implementing-lenet-with-mxnet-in-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/r_notebooks.html&#34;&gt;R Notebook&lt;/a&gt; I implement an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network&#34;&gt;Convolutional Neural Network (CNN)&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://yann.lecun.com/exdb/mnist/&#34;&gt;MNIST Database&lt;/a&gt; for handwritten digits recognition using &lt;a href=&#34;http://mxnet.io/&#34;&gt;mxnet&lt;/a&gt; framework for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Network Analysis on CRAN Authors</title>
      <link>/2018/01/social-network-analysis-on-cran-authors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/social-network-analysis-on-cran-authors/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Este artigo (&lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/r_notebooks.html&#34;&gt;RNotebook&lt;/a&gt;) explora técnicas de &lt;em&gt;Análise de Redes Sociais&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_network_analysis&#34;&gt;SNA&lt;/a&gt;) para analisar o comportamento e organização em redes colaboração de autores e desenvolvedores de pacotes de software para R&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; publicados no repositório CRAN&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting your workout to move</title>
      <link>/2018/01/putting-your-workout-to-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/putting-your-workout-to-move/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;In this quick post, we’ll take one MTB ride, tracked by FitBit in a TXC File, and generate a animated gif. Using &lt;code&gt;gganimate&lt;/code&gt; Package and using the same code we learned, we can animate the map with few words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Collinearity Effect in Regressions</title>
      <link>/2018/01/high-collinearity-effect-in-regressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/high-collinearity-effect-in-regressions/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/htmlwidgets/htmlwidgets.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/plotly-binding/plotly.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/typedarray/typedarray.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/jquery/jquery.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/crosstalk/css/crosstalk.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/crosstalk/js/crosstalk.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/plotlyjs/plotly-htmlwidgets.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/plotlyjs/plotly-latest.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Collinearity refers to the situation in which two or more predictor variables collinearity are closely related to one another. The presence of collinearity can pose problems in the regression context, since it can be difficult to separate out the individual effects of collinear variables on the response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/r_notebooks.html&#34;&gt;R Notebook&lt;/a&gt; seeks to ilustrate some of the difficulties that can be result from a collinearity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ploting your MTB track with R</title>
      <link>/2018/01/ploting-your-mtb-track-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/ploting-your-mtb-track-with-r/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;In this &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/r_notebooks.html&#34;&gt;RNotebook&lt;/a&gt; we’ll read a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training_Center_XML&#34;&gt;TCX&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GPS_Exchange_Format&#34;&gt;GPX&lt;/a&gt; files, used to track physical training and exercises evolving GPS and paths used by some workout Mobile Apps and Devices. Particularly we’ll will process one TCX file containing a MTB ride mine and transforming the a useful R data.frame ploting the ride track over a map.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Giuliano Sposito Myself Computer Engineer and Master in Strategic Management of Technological Innovation, both by Unicamp, and with a specialization in Data Science. Senior Manager at CI&amp;amp;T, current working as Lean Digital Consulting.
My Job Innovation is now everyone&amp;rsquo;s business. If you are a manager in a global company, an entrepreneur starting your business, a team leader, or even a developer within a development team, it is expected that you do more and better with fewer resources (Get Lean!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curse of Dimensionality</title>
      <link>/2018/01/curse-of-dimensionalityrmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/curse-of-dimensionalityrmd/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;This R Notebook reproduces the &lt;strong&gt;Curse of Dimensionality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;nearest neighbor regression&lt;/em&gt; that here is defined as &lt;em&gt;the increasing of the interval size&lt;/em&gt; to get 10% of the data &lt;em&gt;acording with the increasing of dimentions&lt;/em&gt;. So according more dimensions are add to the domain, greater is the size of the range to get the same proportion of data points. Conforming we increase the size of the range we lost “locality” of the information, losing the capacity to resume the information with a simple average.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Model Accuracy (Linear Models)</title>
      <link>/2018/01/assessing-model-accuracy-linear-modelsrmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/assessing-model-accuracy-linear-modelsrmd/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;This post talks about the use of &lt;strong&gt;Mean Squared Error (MSE)&lt;/strong&gt; against the flexibility of a function fitted as a technique to assess the model accuracy in a specific problem as describe in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Introduction-Statistical-Learning-Applications-Statistics/dp/1461471370&#34;&gt;An Introduction to Statistical Learning in R&lt;/a&gt; book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have a blog!</title>
      <link>/2018/01/we-have-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/we-have-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A place to put my ideas and thoughts on the topics that I like and I get involved in everyday life, especially about software development, agility, lean production and data science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>