<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yet Another Iteration</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yet Another Iteration</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Model Accuracy (Linear Models)</title>
      <link>/2018/01/assessing-model-accuracy-linear-modelsrmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/assessing-model-accuracy-linear-modelsrmd/</guid>
      <description>This post talks about the use of Mean Squared Error (MSE) against the flexibility of a function fitted as a technique to assess the model accuracy in a specific problem as describe in the An Introduction to Statistical Learning in R book.
Measure the quality of fit (regression problems)In order to evaluate the performance of a statistical learning method on a given data set, we need some way to measure how well its predictions actually match the observed data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Giuliano Sposito Myself Computer Engineer and Master in Strategic Management of Technological Innovation, both by Unicamp, and with a specialization in Data Science. Senior Manager at CI&amp;amp;T, current working as Lean Digital Consulting.
My Job Innovation is now everyone&amp;rsquo;s business. If you are a manager in a global company, an entrepreneur starting your business, a team leader, or even a developer within a development team, it is expected that you do more and better with fewer resources (Get Lean!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have a blog!</title>
      <link>/2018/01/we-have-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/we-have-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s just a place to put my ideas and thoughts on the topics that I like and I get involved in everyday life, especially about software development, agility, lean production and data science.
When you’ve written the same code 3 times, write a function
When you’ve given the same in-person advice 3 times, write a blog post
&amp;mdash; David Robinson (@drob) November 9, 2017  Yihui Xie, one of the Blogdown package authors tells that we should write a blog to ourselves, we write to us in the future, that writing something makes it more clear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>