<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Yet Another Iteration</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Yet Another Iteration</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading your run and MTB tracks with R</title>
      <link>/2018/01/reading-your-run-and-mtb-tracks-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/reading-your-run-and-mtb-tracks-with-r/</guid>
      <description>In this RNotebook we’ll read a TCX and GPX files, used to track physical training and exercises evolving GPS and paths used by some workout Mobile Apps and Devices.
Tracking FilesThere are two popular file format to track workouts and routes through GPS devices: GPX and TCX.
GPX is an XML format designed specifically for saving GPS track, way point and route data. It is increasingly used by GPS programs because of its flexibility as an XML schema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curse of Dimensionality</title>
      <link>/2018/01/curse-of-dimensionalityrmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/curse-of-dimensionalityrmd/</guid>
      <description>This R Notebook reproduces the Curse of Dimensionality1 in the nearest neighbor regression that here is defined as the increasing of the interval size to get 10% of the data acording with the increasing of dimentions. So according more dimensions are add to the domain, greater is the size of the range to get the same proportion of data points. Conforming we increase the size of the range we lost “locality” of the information, losing the capacity to resume the information with a simple average.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Model Accuracy (Linear Models)</title>
      <link>/2018/01/assessing-model-accuracy-linear-modelsrmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/assessing-model-accuracy-linear-modelsrmd/</guid>
      <description>This post talks about the use of Mean Squared Error (MSE) against the flexibility of a function fitted as a technique to assess the model accuracy in a specific problem as describe in the An Introduction to Statistical Learning in R book.
Measure the quality of fit (regression problems)In order to evaluate the performance of a statistical learning method on a given data set, we need some way to measure how well its predictions actually match the observed data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have a blog!</title>
      <link>/2018/01/we-have-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/we-have-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s just a place to put my ideas and thoughts on the topics that I like and I get involved in everyday life, especially about software development, agility, lean production and data science.
When you’ve written the same code 3 times, write a function
When you’ve given the same in-person advice 3 times, write a blog post
&amp;mdash; David Robinson (@drob) November 9, 2017  Yihui Xie, one of the Blogdown package authors tells that we should write a blog to ourselves, we write to us in the future, that writing something makes it more clear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>